I thought you are all realised souls already.
But how did you get them here,
I don't know.
Are they afraid of
the Albert Hall or what?
All right.
So I think we can try that again.
Just put your hands towards me like that.
Just take out my shoes.
It's all right.
You have to take out your shoes, that's all.
Now as I said yesterday
that another simple thing is that you have to forgive yourself.
As it is, you know it's a fashion to
feel guilty for everything.
I don't know how it has started,
but to feel guilty.
It's a fashion — say "sorry".
Formerly, on the telephone
we used to say, "I beg your pardon,"
all right?
Nowadays they say sorry. Sorry for what?
So this sorryness is too much.
Now don't be sorry for anything here.
You shouldn't feel sorry in any way.
Don't feel guilty.
You have done nothing wrong.
Believe me.
It's all nonsense that you must have read some novel
or might have read some, I don't know what,
that you have to feel guilty.
You are not sinners by any chance,
take it from me.
You are not sinners. It's all just
money-making propositions, I think.
To say you are all sinners, you give us money,
so all your sins will be washed off.
I don't know, they also give guarantee
card I understand.
So all these gimmicks
you must understand.
It has nothing to do with reality.
So just in your heart,
you believe me that you are not sinners.
Not to feel guilty for small, small things.
Our norms are so much that you can
feel guilty for anything.
Say you spilled coffee. Finished.
All your life you are bothered
that I spilled coffee.
I mean coffee is to be spilled only.
I don't understand.
So these stupid nonsensical norms that we
have adopted
are really responsible for creating this feeling of guilt within us also.
Also all funny ideas you read, the books you read and things you read
because you are on the way of righteousness.
You are on the way of reality.
So you start saying,
"Oh my God, I did this.
I should not have done it."
It's all right. Forget it.
If you have done anything wrong at that moment only, you should neutralize it.
But don't carry the load all your
life on your left Vishuddhi.
It's a very dangerous thing
because you develop spondylitis.
If not that, you can develop angina.
So this is a very important centre and
don't feel guilty for no fault of yours.
So this is another very simple condition.
And the third one is, as you forgive yourself for everything,
you should forgive others also.
Because yesterday I told you, whether you
forgive or don't forgive, you don't do anything.
But if you don't forgive others, then
you are playing into wrong hands.
So, just say, "I forgive everyone,"
which is very important because
here people believe that,
"How can I forgive?"
is very difficult.
What is difficult? Nothing.
Just have to say, "Mother, I
forgive everyone." Finished.
Once for all you say that and you'll be
surprised, this centre will open out.
Without these two centres opening up,
the Kundalini cannot pierce through.
So just help yourself with these two things.
Just in your heart you have to say.
Now in your hands just see.
Watch what's happening on your hands.
As I told you yesterday,
all these fingers
are activated when you get your realisation or vibrations.
Because these are all centres of the
sympathetic nervous system endings.
And in these centres what you find is that
these are centres on the right hand side
are for your physical and mental being.
Left hand side are for
your emotional being.
So you can see these five centres,
six and seven.
This is the seventh centre which is here
in the head in the limbic area.
So you have these seven centres
and you start feeling on these seven centres the vibrations, the divine power.
See that.
Now one scientist in Russia I told you yesterday has
found out through his calculations and mathematical things
from my photograph that according to him I am the source of this cosmic energy.
I don't know what to say but whatever it is you just feel it yourself on your fingertips.
Just feel it.
A cool breeze or a hot breeze
will be coming here.